[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "A systems administrator is monitoring an unusual amount of network traffic from a kiosk machine and needs to Investigate to determine the source of the traffic.\nWhich of the following tools can the administrator use to view which processes on the kiosk machine are connecting to the internet?",
    "options": [
      "Resource Monitor",
      "Performance Monitor",
      "Command Prompt",
      "System Information"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Resource Monitor is a tool that shows the network activity of each process on a Windows machine, including the TCP connections and the sent and received\nbytes. Performance Monitor is a tool that shows the performance metrics of the system, such as CPU, memory, disk and network usage. Command Prompt is a\ntool that allows running commands and scripts on a Windows machine. System Information is a tool that shows the hardware and software configuration of a\nWindows machine. Verified References:\nhttps://www.comptia.org/blog/how-to-use-resource-monitor https://www.comptia.org/certifications/a",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following OS types provides a lightweight option for workstations thai need an easy-to-use browser-based interface?",
    "options": [
      "FreeBSD",
      "Chrome OS macOS",
      "",
      "Windows"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Chrome OS provides a lightweight option for workstations that need an easy- to-use browser-based interface1",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "A Linux technician needs a filesystem type that meets the following requirements:\n. All changes are tracked.\n. The possibility of file corruption is reduced.\n· Data recovery is easy.\nWhich of the following filesystem types best meets these requirements?",
    "options": [
      "",
      "FAT32",
      "exFAT",
      "NTFS"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "The ext3 file system is a Linux native file system that meets the requirements of the question. It has the following features:\n? All changes are tracked. The ext3 file system uses a journaling mechanism that\nrecords all changes to the file system metadata in a special log called the journal before applying them to the actual file system. This ensures that the file system\ncan be restored to a consistent state in case of a power failure or system crash12.\n? The possibility of file corruption is reduced. The journaling feature of ext3 also\nreduces the possibility of file corruption, as it avoids the need for a full file system check after an unclean shutdown. The file system can be quickly replayed from\nthe journal and any inconsistencies can be fixed12.\n? Data recovery is easy. The ext3 file system supports undeletion of files using tools\nsuch as ext3grep or extundelete, which can scan the file system for deleted inodes and attempt to recover the data blocks associated with them34.\nReferences:\n1: Introduction to Linux File System [Structure and Types] - MiniTool1 2: 7 Ways to Determine the File System Type in Linux (Ext2, Ext3 or Ext4) - Tecmint3 3:\nHow to Recover Deleted Files in Linux with ext3grep 4: How to Recover Deleted Files from ext3 Partitions",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "A technician installed a new application on a workstation. For the program to function\nproperly, it needs to be listed in the Path Environment Variable. Which of the following Control Panel utilities should the technician use?",
    "options": [
      "System",
      "Indexing Options",
      "Device Manager",
      "Programs and Features"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "System is the Control Panel utility that should be used to change the Path Environment Variable. The Path Environment Variable is a system variable that specifies\nthe directories where executable files are located. To edit the Path Environment Variable, the technician should go to System > Advanced system settings >\nEnvironment Variables and then select Path from the list of system variables and click Edit.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which of the following macOS features can help a user close an application that has stopped responding?",
    "options": [
      "Finder",
      "Mission Control",
      "",
      "Force Quit"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is D. Force Quit. Force Quit is a macOS feature that allows users to close an application that has stopped responding. To use Force Quit,\nusers can press and hold Option (or Alt), Command, and Esc (Escape) keys together, or choose Force Quit from the Apple menu in the corner of the screen. A\nForce Quit window will open, where users can select the application that they want to close and click Force Quit123.\nReferences and Explanation\n? The web search results provide information about how to force an app to quit on\nMac using different methods, such as keyboard shortcuts, mouse clicks, or menu options. The results also explain what to do if the app cannot be forced to quit or\nif the Mac does not respond.\n? The first result1 is from the official Apple Support website and provides detailed\ninstructions and screenshots on how to force an app to quit on Mac using the keyboard shortcut or the Apple menu. It also explains how to force quit the Finder\napp and how to restart or turn off the Mac if needed.\n? The second result2 is from the same website but for a different region (UK). It has\nthe same content as the first result but with some minor differences in spelling and wording.\n? The third result4 is from a website called Lifehacker that provides tips and tricks for\nvarious topics, including technology. It compares how to close a program that is not responding on different operating systems, such as Windows, Mac, and Linux.\nIt briefly mentions how to force quit an app on Mac using the keyboard shortcut or the mouse click.\n? The fourth result3 is from a website called Parallels that provides software\nsolutions for running Windows on Mac. It focuses on how to force quit an app on Mac using the keyboard shortcut and provides a video tutorial and a screenshot\non how to do it. It also suggests some alternative ways to close an app that is not responding, such as using Activity Monitor or Terminal commands.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "100% Valid and Newest Version 220-1102 Questions & Answers shared by Certleader\nA user reports that text on the screen is too small. The user would like to make the text larger and easier to see. Which of the following is the BEST way for the\nuser to increase the size of text, applications, and other items using the Windows 10 Settings tool?",
    "options": [
      "Open Settings select Devices, select Display, and change the display resolution to a lower resolution option",
      "Open Settings, select System, select Display, and change the display resolution to a lower resolution option.",
      "Open Settings Select System, select Display, and change the Scale and layout setting to a higher percentage.",
      "Open Settings select Personalization, select Display and change the Scale and layout setting to a higher percentage"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Open Settings, select System, select Display, and change the Scale and layout setting to a higher percentage123\nReference: 4. How to Increase the Text Size on Your Computer. Retrieved from\nhttps://www.laptopmag.com/articles/increase-text-size-computer 5. How to Change the Size of Text in Windows 10. Retrieved from\nhttps://www.howtogeek.com/370055/how-to- change-the-size-of-text-in-windows-10/ 6. Change the size of text in Windows. Retrieved from\nhttps://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/change-the-size-of-text-in-windows-1d5830c3-eee3-8eaa-836b-abcc37d99b9a",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "A technician is modifying the default home page of all the workstations in a company. Which of the following will help to implement this change?",
    "options": [
      "Group Policy",
      "Browser extension",
      "System Configuration",
      "Task Scheduler"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Group Policy is a feature of Windows that allows administrators to centrally manage and configure the settings of computers and users in a domain network.\nGroup Policy can be used to modify the default home page of all the workstations in a company by creating and applying a policy that specifies the desired URL for\nthe home page. This way, the change will be automatically applied to all the workstations that are joined to the domain and receive the policy.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "A technician is setting up a new laptop. The company's security policy states that users cannot install virtual machines. Which of the following should the technician\nimplement to prevent users from enabling virtual technology on their laptops?",
    "options": [
      "UEFI password",
      "Secure boot",
      "Account lockout",
      "Restricted user permissions"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "A technician setting up a new laptop must ensure that users cannot install virtual machines as the company's security policy states One way to prevent users from\nenabling virtual technology is by implementing Secure Boot. Secure Boot is a feature of UEFI firmware that ensures the system only boots using firmware that is\ntrusted by the manufacturer. It verifies the signature of all bootloaders, operating systems, and drivers before running them, preventing any unauthorized\nmodifications to the boot process. This will help prevent users from installing virtual machines on the laptop without authorization.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which of the following filesystems replaced FAT as the preferred filesystem for Microsoft Windows OS?",
    "options": [
      "APFS",
      "FAT32",
      "NTFS",
      "ext4"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "NTFS stands for New Technology File System and it is the preferred filesystem for Microsoft Windows OS since Windows NT 3.1 in 19931. NTFS replaced FAT\n(File Allocation Table) as the default filesystem for Windows because it offers many advantages over FAT, such as:\n? Support for larger volumes and files (up to 16 exabytes)2\n? Support for file compression, encryption, and permissions2\n? Support for journaling, which records changes to the filesystem and helps recover from errors2\n? Support for hard links, symbolic links, and mount points2\n? Support for long filenames and Unicode characters2\nFAT32 is an improved version of FAT that supports larger volumes and files (up to 32 GB and 4 GB respectively) and is compatible with older versions of Windows\nand other operating systems3. However, FAT32 still has many limitations and drawbacks compared\nto NTFS, such as:\n? No support for file compression, encryption, and permissions3\n? No support for journaling, which makes it vulnerable to corruption and data loss3\n? No support for hard links, symbolic links, and mount points3\n? No support for long filenames and Unicode characters3\nAPFS (Apple File System) is the default filesystem for macOS, iOS, iPadOS, watchOS, and tvOS since 20174. APFS replaced HFS+ (Hierarchical File System\nPlus) as the preferred filesystem for Apple devices because it offers many advantages over HFS+, such as:\n? Support for larger volumes and files (up to 8 zettabytes)4\n? Support for file cloning, snapshots, and encryption4\n? Support for space sharing, which allows multiple volumes to share the same storage pool4\n? Support for fast directory sizing, which improves performance and efficiency4 ext4 (Fourth Extended Filesystem) is the default filesystem for most Linux\ndistributions since 20085. ext4 replaced ext3 as the preferred filesystem for Linux because it offers many advantages over ext3, such as:\n? Support for larger volumes and files (up to 1 exabyte and 16 terabytes respectively)5\n? Support for extents, which reduce fragmentation and improve performance5\n? Support for journal checksumming, which improves reliability and reduces recovery time5\n? Support for delayed allocation, which improves efficiency and reduces metadata overhead5\nReferences:\n1: NTFS - Wikipedia 2: [NTFS vs FAT32 vs exFAT: What’s the Difference?] 3: [FAT32 - Wikipedia] 4: [Apple File System - Wikipedia] 5: [ext4 - Wikipedia] : NTFS\nvs FAT32 vs exFAT: What’s the Difference? : FAT32 - Wikipedia : Apple File System - Wikipedia : ext4 - Wikipedia",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "An IT security team is implementing a new Group Policy that will return a computer to the login after three minutes. Which of the following BEST describes the\nchange in policy?",
    "options": [
      "Login times",
      "Screen lock",
      "User permission",
      "Login lockout attempts"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Screen lock is a feature that returns a computer to the login screen after a period of inactivity, requiring the user to enter their credentials to resume their session.\nScreen lock can be configured using Group Policy settings, such as Screen saver timeout and Interactive logon: Machine inactivity limit. Screen lock can help\nprevent unauthorized access to a computer when the user is away from their desk. Login times are not a feature that returns a computer to the login screen, but a\nmeasure of how long it takes for a user to log in to a system. User permission is not a feature that returns a computer to the login screen, but a set of rights and\nprivileges that determine what a user can do on a system. Login lockout attempts are not a feature that returns a computer to the login screen, but a security policy\nthat locks out a user account after a number of failed login attempts. https://woshub.com/windows-lock-screen-after-idle-via-gpo/",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST likely used to run .vbs files on Windows devices?",
    "options": [
      "winmgmt.exe",
      "powershell.exe",
      "cscript.exe",
      "explorer.exe"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "A .vbs file is a Virtual Basic script written in the VBScript scripting language. It contains code that can be executed within Windows via the Windows-based script\nhost (Wscript.exe), to perform certain admin and processing functions1. Cscript.exe is a command-line version of the Windows Script Host that provides command-\nline options for setting script properties. Therefore, cscript.exe is most likely used to run .vbs files on Windows devices. References: 1:\nhttps://fileinfo.com/extension/vbs : https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/administration/windows- commands/cscript",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "A user recently purchased a second monitor and wants to extend the Windows desktop to the new screen. Which of the following Control Panel options should a\ntechnician adjust to help the user?",
    "options": [
      "Color Management System",
      "",
      "Troubleshooting",
      "Device Manager",
      "Administrative Tools"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "As part of a CYOD policy a systems administrator needs to configure each user's Windows device to require a password when resuming from a period of sleep or\ninactivity. Which of the following paths will lead the administrator to the correct settings?",
    "options": [
      "Use Settings to access Screensaver settings",
      "Use Settings to access Screen Timeout settings",
      "Use Settings to access General",
      "Use Settings to access Display."
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "The systems administrator should use Settings to access Screensaver settings to configure each user’s Windows device to require a password when resuming\nfrom a period of sleep or inactivity1",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "A technician downloaded software from the Internet that required the technician to scroll through a text box and at the end of the text box, click a button labeled\nAccept Which of the following agreements IS MOST likely in use?",
    "options": [
      "Mastered",
      "Not Mastered"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "The most likely agreement in use here is a EULA (End User License Agreement). This is a legally binding agreement between the user and the software\ndeveloper, outlining the terms and conditions that the user must agree to in order to use the software. It is important that the user understands and agrees to the\nEULA before they can proceed with downloading and installing the software. As stated in the CompTIA A+ Core 2 exam objectives, users should be aware of the\nEULA before downloading any software.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Which of the following default system tools can be used in macOS to allow the technician to view the screen simultaneously with the user?",
    "options": [
      "Remote Assistance Remote Desktop Protocol",
      "",
      "Screen Sharing",
      "Virtual Network Computing"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Screen Sharing is the default system tool that can be used in macOS to allow the technician to view the screen simultaneously with the user. Screen Sharing is a\nbuilt-in app that lets users share their Mac screen with another Mac on the network. The user can enable screen sharing in the System Preferences > Sharing\npane, and then allow other users to request or enter a password to access their screen1. The technician can launch the Screen Sharing app from the Spotlight\nsearch or the Finder sidebar, and then enter the user’s name, address, or Apple ID to connect to their screen2. Remote Assistance is a Windows feature that\nallows users to invite someone to help them with a problem on their PC3. Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP) is a protocol that allows users to connect to a remote\ncomputer over a network4. Virtual Network Computing (VNC) is a technology that allows users to share their screen with other devices using a VNC viewer app1.\nThese are not default system tools in macOS, although they can be used with third-party software or settings.\nReferences: 1: https://support.apple.com/guide/mac-help/share-the-screen-of-another-mac-\nmh14066/mac 2: https://www.howtogeek.com/449239/how-to-share-your-macs-screen-\nwith-another-mac/ 3: https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/solve-pc-problems-over-\na-remote-connection-b077e31a-16f4-2529-1a47-21f6a9040bf3 4: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/remote/remote-desktop-services/clients/remote-\ndesktop-protocol",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "A technician is creating a location on a Windows workstation for a customer to store meeting minutes. Which of the following commands should the technician\nuse?",
    "options": [
      "c: \\minutes",
      "dir rmdir",
      "",
      "md"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "The command md stands for make directory and is used to create a new directory or folder in the current location. In this case, the technician can use md minutes\nto create a folder named minutes in the C: drive. The other commands are not relevant for\nthis task. c: \\minutes is not a command but a path to a folder. dir is used to display a list of files and folders in the current directory. rmdir is used to remove or\ndelete an existing directory or folder.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "A technician is trying to connect to a user's laptop in order to securely install updates. Given the following information about the laptop:\nWhich of the following should the technician do to connect via RDP?",
    "options": [
      "Confirm the user can ping the default gateway.",
      "Change the IP address on the user's laptop.",
      "Change the subnet mask on the user's laptop.",
      "Open port 3389 on the Windows firewall."
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "In order to connect to a user’s laptop via RDP, the technician should open port 3389 on the Windows firewall. This is because RDP uses port 3389 for\ncommunication12. The other options are not necessary or relevant for establishing an RDP connection.\n? Confirming the user can ping the default gateway is not required for RDP, as it\nonly tests the network connectivity between the user’s laptop and the router. RDP works over the internet, so the technician should be able to ping the user’s\nlaptop directly using its IP address3.\n? Changing the IP address on the user’s laptop is not needed for RDP, as long as\nthe IP address is valid and not conflicting with another device on the network. The user’s laptop has a valid IP address of 192.168.0.45, which belongs to the\nsame subnet as the gateway (192.168.0.1) and the subnet mask (255.255.255.0)4.\n? Changing the subnet mask on the user’s laptop is not required for RDP, as long as\nthe subnet mask matches the network configuration. The user’s laptop has a correct subnet mask of 255.255.255.0, which defines a network with 254 possible\nhosts4.\nReferences:\n1: [What is RDP and How Does It Work? - CompTIA] 2: CompTIA A+ Certification Exam Core 2 Objectives - CompTIA 3: [Ping (networking utility) - Wikipedia] 4:\n[IP address - Wikipedia] : What is RDP and How Does It Work? - CompTIA : CompTIA A+ Certification Exam Core 2 Objectives - CompTIA : Ping (networking\nutility) - Wikipedia) : IP address - Wikipedia\n100% Valid and Newest Version 220-1102 Questions & Answers shared by Certleader",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Which of the following filesystem types does macOS use?",
    "options": [
      "ext4",
      "exFAT",
      "NTFS",
      "APFS"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "APFS stands for Apple File System and it is the default filesystem type for macOS since High Sierra (10.13) version1. APFS is optimized for flash storage and\nsupports features such as encryption, snapshots, cloning, and space sharing1.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "A developer's Type 2 hypervisor is performing inadequately when compiling new source code. Which of the following components should the developer upgrade to\nimprove the hypervisor’s performance?",
    "options": [
      "Amount of system RAM",
      "NIC performance",
      "Storage IOPS",
      "Dedicated GPU"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "The correct answer is A. Amount of system RAM. A Type 2 hypervisor is a virtualization software that runs on top of a host operating system, which means it\nshares the system resources with the host OS and other applications. Therefore, increasing the amount of system RAM can improve the performance of the\n100% Valid and Newest Version 220-1102 Questions & Answers shared by Certleader\nhypervisor and the virtual machines running on it. RAM is used to store data and instructions that are frequently accessed by the CPU, and having more RAM can\nreduce the need for swapping data to and from the storage device, which is slower than RAM.\nNIC performance, storage IOPS, and dedicated GPU are not as relevant for improving the hypervisor’s performance in this scenario. NIC performance refers to\nthe speed and quality of the network interface card, which is used to connect the computer to a network. Storage IOPS refers to the number of input/output\noperations per second that can be performed by the storage device, which is a measure of its speed and efficiency. Dedicated GPU refers to a separate graphics\ngaming or video editing. These components may affect other aspects\nprocessing unit that can handle complex graphics tasks, such as\nof the computer’s performance, but they are not directly related to the hypervisor’s ability to compile new source code.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "A technician is setting up a desktop computer in a small office. The user will need to\naccess files on a drive shared from another desktop on the network. Which of the following configurations should the technician employ\nto achieve this goal?",
    "options": [
      "Configure the network as private",
      "Enable a proxy server",
      "Grant the network administrator role to the user",
      "Create a shortcut to public documents"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "The technician should configure the network as private to allow the user to access files on a drive shared from another desktop on the network1",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "A technician is setting up a newly built computer. Which of the following is the fastest way for the technician to install Windows 10?",
    "options": [
      "Factory reset",
      "System Restore",
      "In-place upgrade",
      "Unattended installation"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Windows 10\n100% Valid and Newest Version 220-1102 Questions & Answers shared by Certleader\nThe correct answer is D. Unattended installation. An unattended installation is a way of installing Windows 10 without requiring any user input or interaction. It uses\na configuration file called answer file that contains the settings and preferences for the installation, such as the product key, language, partition, and network\nsettings. An unattended installation can be performed by using a bootable USB flash drive or DVD that contains the Windows 10 installation files and the answer\nfile1. This is the fastest way for the technician to install Windows 10 on a newly built computer, as it automates the whole process and saves time. A factory reset\nis a way of restoring a computer to its original state by deleting all the data and applications and reinstalling the operating system. A factory reset can be performed\nby using the recovery partition or media that came with the computer, or by using the Reset this PC option in Windows 10 settings2. A factory reset is not a way of\ninstalling Windows 10 on a newly built computer, as it requires an existing operating system to be present.\nA system restore is a way of undoing changes to a computer’s system files and settings by using a restore point that was created earlier. A system restore can be\nperformed by using the System Restore option in Windows 10 settings or by using the Advanced Startup Options menu3. A system restore is not a way of\ninstalling Windows 10 on a newly built computer, as it requires an existing operating system and restore points to be present.\nAn in-place upgrade is a way of upgrading an existing operating system to a newer version without losing any data or applications. An in-place upgrade can be\nperformed by using the Windows 10 Media Creation Tool or by running the Setup.exe file from the Windows 10 installation media. An in-place upgrade is not a\nway of installing Windows 10 on a newly built computer, as it requires an existing operating system to be present.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which of the following Is a package management utility for PCs that are running the Linux operating system?",
    "options": [
      "chmod",
      "yum",
      "man",
      "grep"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "yum (Yellowdog Updater Modified) is a package management utility for PCs that are running the Linux operating system. It can be used to install, update and\nremove software packages from repositories. chmod (change mode) is a command that changes the permissions of files and directories in Linux. man (manual) is\na command that displays the documentation of other commands in Linux. grep (global regular expression print) is a command that searches for patterns in text\nfiles in Linux. Verified References: https://www.comptia.org/blog/linux-package-management https://www.comptia.org/certifications/a",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "A user installed a new application that automatically starts each time the user logs in to a Windows 10 system. The user does not want this to happen and has\nasked for this setting to be changed. Which of the following tools would the technician MOST likely use to safely make this change?",
    "options": [
      "Mastered",
      "Not Mastered"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "The technician would most likely use the Task Manager tool to safely make this change12\nThe Task Manager tool can be used to disable applications from starting automatically on Windows 10\nThe tool that a technician would most likely use to stop an application from automatically starting when a user logs in to a Windows 10 system is the Task\nManager. The Task Manager can be used to view and manage processes, including those that are set to automatically start when a user logs in to the system.",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "A user has a computer with Windows 10 Home installed and purchased a Windows 10 Pro license. The user is not sure how to upgrade the OS. Which of the\nfollowing should the technician do to apply this license?",
    "options": [
      "Copy the c:\\Wlndows\\wlndows.lie file over to the machine and restart.",
      "Redeem the included activation key card for a product key.",
      "Insert a Windows USB hardware dongle and initiate activation.",
      "Activate with the digital license included with the device hardware."
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Redeeming the included activation key card for a product key is the correct way to apply a Windows 10 Pro license to a computer that has Windows 10 Home\ninstalled. The activation key card is a physical or digital card that contains a 25-digit code that can be used to activate Windows 10 Pro online or by phone.\nCopying the windows.lie file, inserting a Windows USB hardware dongle and activating with the digital license are not valid methods of applying a Windows 10 Pro\nlicense. Verified References: https://www.comptia.org/blog/how-to-upgrade-windows-10-home-to-pro https://www.comptia.org/certifications/a",
    "source_pdf": "220-1102_1.pdf",
    "type": "single",
    "topic": "operating-systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Which of these Windows features provides full disk encryption for all data on a storage drive?",
    "options": [
      "Domain Services",
      "EFS",
      "RDP",
      "BitLocker"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "BitLocker BitLocker provides full disk encryption (FDE) for Windows operating system volumes. The incorrect answers: A. Domain Services Windows Domain Services are used as a centralized database for management of large-scale Windows implementations. Domain Services itself is not an encryption mechanism. B. EFS EFS (Encrypting File System) is a feature of the NTFS (NT File System) that provides encryption at the file system level. Individual files and folders can be encrypted in Windows using EFS. C. RDP RDP (Remote Desktop Protocol) is commonly used to remotely control the desktop of a Windows computer. RDP is not used for encryption of files on the system. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.1 - Windows Features https://professormesser.link/1102010102 Practice Exam A - Answers 49",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A13"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the maximum amount of RAM supported by a 32-bit version of an operating system?",
    "options": [
      "4 GB",
      "8 GB",
      "16 GB",
      "192 GB"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "4 GB The limited address space of a 32-bit operating system can only support 4 GB of system memory. The incorrect answers: B. 8 GB A 32-bit operating system is limited to 4 GB of addressable memory. Although there are some techniques to work around this 4 GB limitation, they're not often implemented in practice. C. 16 GB 4 GB is the limit for 32-bit operating systems. D. 192 GB 192 GB would be well over the limit for 32-bit operating systems. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.7 - Installing Applications https://professormesser.link/1102010701 Practice Exam A - Answers 55",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A19"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Daniel, a user, is attempting to start an application on his laptop computer. Each time the application shows the starting graphic, it suddenly disappears and the application icon disappears from the taskbar. A technician would like to get more information about each previous occurrence of the application crash. Which of these choices would provide these details?",
    "options": [
      "Event Viewer",
      "Task Manager",
      "Startup Repair",
      "Safe Mode"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Event Viewer Event Viewer contains a consolidated log of all system and application logs. A technician can use Event Viewer to review all past events on the system. The incorrect answers: B. Task Manager Task Manager provides a real-time view of performance across many different system metrics, but it doesn't provide a way to review historical performance or events. C. Startup Repair Startup Repair is a useful tool when a system is not able to boot. Startup Repair does not resolve problems with applications that will not properly start. D. Safe Mode Safe Mode useful for testing in a minimal operating system environment, but it doesn't provide any additional method of viewing application crash event logs. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 56 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A20"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "A system administrator has created a shared folder on a server to store operating system images. Technicians access the shared folder to download the latest images when performing large-scale system installations. Which of the following will be the MOST likely method of accessing this data?",
    "options": [
      "Map the shared folder to an available drive letter",
      "Download the shared folder through a proxy",
      "Link the images to a cloud storage service",
      "Access the folder using a remote access client"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Map the shared folder to an available drive letter The easiest and most efficient way for technicians to access the drive share is to map a drive letter to the share and transfer the files directly. The incorrect answers: B. Download the shared folder through a proxy There's no mention of a proxy in the question, and adding a proxy to this process would not provide any additional features or benefits. C. Link the images to a cloud storage service Operating system images are relatively large, and transferring them to an external cloud-based service would add additional time and bandwidth to resources that are already located on a local file server. D. Access the folder using a remote access client The installation of an operating system requires direct access to the installation files, and a remote access client would not provide direct access to the files. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.6 - Windows Network Technologies https://professormesser.link/1102010601 60 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A24"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "A desktop administrator is installing a 64-bit version of Windows 10 Pro on a workstation, but the installation will not start. The workstation configuration is: 1 GHz CPU 2 GB of RAM 15 GB of free storage space 1280 x 720 video resolution Which of the following would allow this installation to proceed?",
    "options": [
      "Increase free storage space to 32 GB",
      "Decrease resolution to 800 x 600",
      "Upgrade to a faster processor",
      "Increase RAM to 4 GB"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Increase free storage space to 32 GB The latest version of Windows 10 x64 requires a minimum of 32 GB free storage space. The incorrect answers: B. Decrease resolution to 800 x 600 The only video requirement for the Windows 10 installation process is a Microsoft DirectX 9 graphics device with a WDDM driver. C. Upgrade to a faster processor The minimum supported processor to install Windows 10 is a 1 GHz CPU. D. Increase RAM to 4 GB The minimum RAM required to install Windows 10 x64 is 2 GB. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.1 - An Overview of Windows https://professormesser.link/1102010101 Practice Exam A - Answers 61",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A25"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "A system administrator has been asked to install a new application on a server, but the application is 64-bit and the server operating system is 32-bit. Which of the following describes the issue associated with this installation?",
    "options": [
      "File permissions",
      "OS compatibility",
      "Installation method",
      "Available drive space"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "OS compatibility Although 32-bit applications will run on a 64-bit operating system, the reverse is not true. A 64-bit application will require a 64-bit operating system to work. The incorrect answers: A. File permissions File permissions between a 32-bit operating system and a 64-bit operating system are effectively identical. C. Installation method There isn't any significant difference when installing an application on a 32-bit operating system or a 64-bit operating system. D. Available drive space Although there will be a slight difference in drive space requirements between a 32-bit application and a 64-bit application, the differences would not be enough to cause an issue with free drive space. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.7 - Installing Applications https://professormesser.link/1102010701 Practice Exam A - Answers 65",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A29"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "A Linux administrator needs to modify the configuration text file for a service. Which of the following utilities would provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "nano",
      "chmod",
      "df",
      "sudo"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "nano The nano utility is a full-screen text editor that can be used from the command line of a Linux device. The incorrect answers: B. chmod The chmod (Change Mode) utility is used to modify the read, write, or execution permissions of an object in the Linux file system. C. df The df (Disk Free) utility provides a view of available filesystems and the free disk space in each filesystem. D. sudo The sudo command allows a Linux user to execute a command as the superuser or as any other user on the system. The sudo command on its own does not provide any backup or imaging functionality. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.11 - Linux Commands https://professormesser.link/1102011101 Practice Exam A - Answers 67",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A31"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "A user has installed multiple applications over the last week. During the startup process, the computer now takes over fifteen minutes to display the Windows 10 desktop. Which of the following utilities would help the system administrator troubleshoot this issue?",
    "options": [
      "defrag",
      "Performance Monitor",
      "Task Manager",
      "robocopy"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Task Manager The Task Manager includes a Startup tab for managing the applications that launch during the Windows login process. The incorrect answers: A. defrag Although a fragmented drive can cause minor inefficiencies when accessing data, it would not cause a system delay of over fifteen minutes during the boot process. B. Performance Monitor The Performance Monitor utility is designed to collect metrics over an extended period of time. Performance Monitor does not provide any management or control of the startup process. D. robocopy Robocopy (Robust Copy) is an advanced copy utility used to transfer files between folders or systems. The robocopy utility would not provide any significant troubleshooting assistance with this slowdown issue. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 - Task Manager https://professormesser.link/1102010301 Practice Exam A - Answers 73",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A37"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "A system administrator needs to view a set of application log files contained in a folder named “logs.” Which of the following commands should be used to make this folder the current directory?",
    "options": [
      "cd logs",
      "mv logs",
      "dir logs",
      "md logs"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "cd logs The \"cd\" command is short for change working directory, and it can be used in Windows or Linux to move around the file system. The incorrect answers: B. mv logs The mv command is commonly used in Linux to \"move\" a file from one place to another, or to rename an existing file from one name to another. C. dir logs The dir (directory) command will list files and directories in a folder. If the command specifies additional text, the results will be filtered for that specific text. D. md logs The Windows md command is an abbreviation of the mkdir (make directory) command. The md command will create a folder in the file system. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.2 - Windows Command Line Tools https://professormesser.link/1102010201 76 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A40"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "A system administrator is configuring a server to use eight bootable partitions on a single SSD. Which of the following partition styles would be the BEST choice for this configuration?",
    "options": [
      "MBR",
      "NTFS",
      "diskpart",
      "GPT"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "GPT The GPT ( GUID Partition Table) partition style allows for up to 128 separate bootable partitions. The incorrect answers: A. MBR The MBR (Master Boot Record) partition style provides a maximum of four bootable primary partitions per drive. B. NTFS NTFS (NT File System) is a file system designed for Windows computers. Although a system may store files using NTFS, the partition style containing the NTFS file system would determine the maximum number of supported partitions. C. diskpart The diskpart utility is a command line option for managing partition styles and bootable configurations. Although diskpart can be used to configure a partition style, the diskpart utility itself is not a partition. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 Practice Exam A - Answers 77",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A41"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "A technician is installing a fresh Windows operating system on a file server. Unfortunately, the drive controller in the system is not recognized during the installation process. Which of the following would be the BEST way to manage this issue?",
    "options": [
      "Load third-party drivers",
      "Restart the system",
      "Use a remote network installation",
      "Boot from the recovery partition"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Load third-party drivers The Windows installation program includes drivers for most hardware devices, but occasionally additional device drivers will need to be added during the installation process. The incorrect answers: B. Restart the system The installation program will still be unable to access the drive controller after a reboot, so restarting the system is an unlikely solution to this issue. C. Use a remote network installation Installing Windows across the network can simplify the use of installation media, but it won't provide any additional access to the drive controller. D. Boot from the recovery partition Since Windows has not yet been installed on this system, it's unlikely a recovery partition exists. Even if a recovery partition does exist, the installation program will still not have device drivers for the drive controller. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 78 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A42"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "The hard drive in a macOS desktop has failed and none of the data on the drive was recoverable. A new storage drive has now been installed. Which of the following should be used to restore the data on the computer?",
    "options": [
      "Backup and Restore",
      "Mission Control",
      "Time Machine",
      "Disk Utility"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Time Machine The built-in backup and restore utility in macOS is appropriately called Time Machine. The incorrect answers: A. Backup and Restore The Windows operating system includes its own backup and recovery utility called \"Backup and Restore.\" B. Mission Control Mission Control is an easy way to view all open applications and virtual desktops in macOS. D. Disk Utility Disk Utility is a macOS tool that allows the user to view, modify, and manage storage drives. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.10 - macOS System Preferences https://professormesser.link/1102011002 Practice Exam A - Answers 81",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A45"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "A system administrator is upgrading four workstations from Windows 8.1 to Windows 11. All of the user files and applications are stored on the server, and no documents or settings need to be retained between versions. Which of these installation methods would be the BEST way to provide this upgrade?",
    "options": [
      "Factory reset",
      "Repair installation",
      "Clean install",
      "In-place upgrade"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Clean install A clean install of Windows 11 will completely delete the previous operating system and install a new installation of the Windows 11 operating system. The previous Windows 8.1 operating system will no longer be available on the computer. The incorrect answers: A. Factory reset A factory reset will restore the computer to the configuration from the original purchase. In this example, the factory reset will refresh the existing Windows 8.1 installation (or a previous version), instead of installing Windows 11. B. Repair installation A repair installation installs the current version of the operating system over itself in an effort to repair files that may have been deleted or damaged. This repair installation will not upgrade an operating system to a newer version. D. In-place upgrade Some Windows versions allow an in-place upgrade process to keep user applications and data available after the upgrade is complete. Unfortunately, there are no in-place upgrades available between Windows 8.1 and Windows 11. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.1 - Windows Upgrades https://professormesser.link/1102010103 Practice Exam A - Answers 83",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A47"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "An administrator is upgrading a Windows 8.1 Enterprise x64 computer to Windows 10. The user would like to maintain all applications and files during the upgrade process. Which of the following upgrade options would meet this requirement?",
    "options": [
      "Windows 10 Enterprise x86",
      "Windows 10 Pro x64",
      "Windows 10 Enterprise x64",
      "Windows 10 Pro x86"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Windows 10 Enterprise x64 A Windows upgrade that maintains applications and settings requires the destination version to be the same Windows edition or higher. Since the original Windows 8.1 is the Enterprise edition, the Windows 10 edition should also be the Enterprise version. It's also not possible to upgrade from a 32-bit version to 64-bit (or vice versa), so the Windows 10 operating system needs to be the x64 version. The incorrect answers: A. Windows 10 Enterprise x86 A 64-bit operating system cannot upgrade to a 32-bit version (or vice versa). B. Windows 10 Pro x64 Since the starting Windows 8.1 edition is the Enterprise version, the final operating system must also be the same or higher. Windows 10 Pro is not the same or higher edition as Windows 8.1 Enterprise edition. D. Windows 10 Pro x86 As with option B, the Pro edition of Windows 10 is not the same or higher edition as Windows 8.1 Enterprise. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.1 - Windows Upgrades https://professormesser.link/1102010103 86 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A50"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "A user in the marketing department is using an application that randomly shuts down during normal use. When the problem occurs, the application suddenly disappears and no error messages are shown on the screen. Which of the following would provide the system administrator with additional information regarding this issue?",
    "options": [
      "System Configuration",
      "Event Viewer",
      "Device Manager",
      "Group Policy Editor",
      "SFC"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Event Viewer The Windows Event Viewer can provide extensive logs and information about the system and the applications running in Windows. The incorrect answers: A. System Configuration The System Configuration utility can provide an easy interface to modify boot settings and services, but it won't provide any additional details about this application problem. C. Device Manager The Device Manager is used to control and manage hardware and device drivers. Device Manager doesn't contain any detailed information about problematic applications. D. Group Policy Editor The Windows Group Policy Editor can be used to create or modify Group Policy settings on remote devices. Group Policy Editor does not provide any information about application failures. E. SFC SFC (System File Checker) is used to verify that the core operating system files are valid. Application information isn't part of the SFC utility. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 Practice Exam A - Answers 87",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A51"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "A user working from home is not able to print to a laser printer at the corporate office. Which of the following would be the MOST likely reason for this issue?",
    "options": [
      "WPA3 settings",
      "Outdated anti-virus signatures",
      "Disconnected VPN",
      "MDM configuration"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Disconnected VPN Remote users will commonly connect to the corporate office over a VPN (Virtual Private Network). This VPN is an encrypted tunnel and all traffic between the locations is protected from anyone monitoring the connection. If the VPN link is not active, then the remote user will be unable to use any resources at the corporate office. The incorrect answers: A. WPA3 settings WPA3 (Wi-Fi Protected Access 3) is a standard for wireless encryption and security. WPA3 would not be involved in a printing problem across a VPN to a corporate office. B. Outdated anti-virus signatures Anti-virus signatures would not commonly restrict the printing process, and the age of the signatures would only affect the ability of the anti-virus software to block known viruses. D. MDM configuration An MDM (Mobile Device Manager) is used to manage mobile tablets and phones. MDM configurations would not commonly have an impact on home users connecting to a corporate printer. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.6 - Windows Network Connections https://professormesser.link/1102010604 90 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A54"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "A malware infection has recently been removed from a computer. When starting the operating system, Windows shows errors during the startup process indicating some core operating system files are missing. Which of the following should be used to restore these missing files?",
    "options": [
      "gpupdate",
      "winver",
      "sfc",
      "diskpart"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "sfc The sfc (System File Checker) command is used to scan and replace any core operating system files which may be corrupted or missing. It's common to run the sfc utility after removing malware or after a significant operating system issue. The incorrect answers: A. gpupdate The gpupdate (Group Policy Update) command is used to force a Group Policy update to computers in a Windows Active Directory domain. The gpupdate command would not restore any missing operating system files. B. winver The winver (Windows Version) command line utility will display the \"About Windows\" dialog box on the screen. D. diskpart An administrator can manage disk configurations and partitions with the Windows diskpart utility. The diskpart utility is not used to restore or modify files within the Windows operating system. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.2 - Windows Command Line Tools https://professormesser.link/1102010201 100 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A64"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "A system administrator is creating a series of shared folders that should not be visible when users browse the network for available resources. What symbol should be added to the end of a share name to provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      ". (period)",
      "$ (dollar sign)",
      "! (exclamation mark / bang)",
      "# (hash sign / number sign)"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "$ (dollar sign) Windows shares ending with a dollar sign ($) are hidden and won't be shown in the normal list of available shares. The hidden share can still be accessed if the user knows the share name, so this should not be considered a security feature. The incorrect answers: A. . (period) Ending the Windows share with a period is not supported. C. ! (exclamation mark / bang) Using the exclamation mark in a share name is not supported. D. # (hash sign / number sign) The hash sign is not allowed in a share name. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.6 - Windows Network Technologies https://professormesser.link/1102010601 Practice Exam A - Answers 103",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A67"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "A technician is troubleshooting a computer infected with a virus. The user thought they were opening a spreadsheet, but the file was actually a virus executable. Which of the following Windows options were MOST likely associated with this issue?",
    "options": [
      "Always show icons, never thumbnails",
      "Display the full path in the title bar",
      "Always show menus",
      "Hide extensions for known file types"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Hide extensions for known file types With extensions hidden, it's difficult to know the type of file based only on the filename. A filename named \"Monthly Orders\" might be a spreadsheet, or it could be an executable containing a virus. The incorrect answers: A. Always show icons, never thumbnails Showing icons instead of thumbnails can still be a way to hide information. For example, it's relatively easy to create an executable that uses the same icon as a spreadsheet. B. Display the full path in the title bar The full path in the title bar shows where the file is located on the volume, but it doesn't provide any information about the contents of the file. C. Always show menus The Windows menus are useful, but the menus themselves don't provide any additional information about the contents of a particular file. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Control Panel https://professormesser.link/1102010401 Practice Exam A - Answers 107",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A71"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "A system administrator is adding an additional drive to a server and extending the size of an existing volume. Which of the following utilities would provide a graphical summary of the existing storage configuration?",
    "options": [
      "Disk Management",
      "Performance Monitor",
      "Event Viewer",
      "Task Scheduler",
      "Device Manager"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Disk Management The Disk Management utility provides a graphical overview of the current disk configuration, status, free space, and other important metrics. The incorrect answers: B. Performance Monitor The Performance Monitor provides a historical summary of system performance and resource utilization. C. Event Viewer The Event Viewer maintains all of the application and system logs for Windows devices. D. Task Scheduler The Windows Task Scheduler can automate scripts and applications to run at predetermined times. E. Device Manager The Windows Device Manager is the management interface to the device drivers and other hardware components. The storage drives are not managed through the Device Manager More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 Practice Exam A - Answers 115",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A78"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "A system administrator needs to upgrade a training room of twenty systems to the latest Windows version. Which of the following would be the MOST efficient method of performing this upgrade process?",
    "options": [
      "Recovery partition",
      "Remote network installation",
      "Repair installation",
      "USB key"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Remote network installation A single network server can provide access for simultaneous upgrades. With additional customization, the upgrade process can be completely hands-off and can execute on all systems at the same time. The incorrect answers: A. Recovery partition A recovery partition does not generally provide a method of upgrading an operating system, and it requires each system to be accessed locally during the installation. C. Repair installation A repair installation does not upgrade an operating system, and it usually requires intervention on each system to complete the repair process. D. USB key USB media is an efficient method of accessing a large number of files, but it either requires the administrator to upgrade one system at a time or it requires twenty separate USB keys to perform the upgrade. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 Practice Exam A - Answers 117",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A80"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "A Linux administrator has been asked to upgrade the web server software on a device. Which of the following would provide the administrator with the appropriate rights and permissions for this upgrade?",
    "options": [
      "chmod",
      "apt-get",
      "dig",
      "sudo"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "sudo The sudo (superuser do) command will execute a command as the superuser or any other user on the system. When performing administrative tasks such as upgrading software, it's often necessary to use elevated rights and permissions. The incorrect answers: A. chmod The chmod (change mode) command will modify the read, write, and execution permissions for a file system object. The mode of a file or folder would not commonly need to be modified during an upgrade. B. apt-get The apt-get (Advanced Packaging Tool) command is used to manage application packages and software upgrades. The apt-get command does not provide any additional rights and permissions, however. C. dig The dig (Domain Information Groper) command is used to query a DNS (Domain Name System) server for IP address or fully-qualified domain name details. The dig command does not provide any additional permissions. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.11 - Linux Commands https://professormesser.link/1102011101 122 Practice Exam A - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A85"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "A user is connecting their laptop to an external monitor and keyboard, but the laptop goes into sleep mode if the laptop screen is shut. Which of the following would modify this configuration to keep the laptop running when the lid is closed?",
    "options": [
      "Power Options",
      "Device Manager",
      "Personalization",
      "User Accounts"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Power Options The Control Panel's Power Options provide configuration settings for the sleep button, the power button, and the options when closing the lid of a laptop computer. The incorrect answers: B. Device Manager The Device Manager is used to install or update device drivers for hardware on a Windows computer. C. Personalization The Windows Settings include Personalization options for changing the way Windows looks and feels. This includes colors, wallpaper, the lock screen, and other user interface settings. D. User Accounts Account name, picture, password, and certificate information can be found in the Control Panel's User Accounts applet. The User Accounts setting does not provide any configuration options for the laptop screen. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Control Panel https://professormesser.link/1102010401 Practice Exam A - Answers 123",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "A86"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "A user needs to modify a spreadsheet for an upcoming meeting. The spreadsheet is currently stored on a remote computer in a shared drive. The user would like to access the shared drive as a drive letter inside of Windows File Explorer. Which of the following command line options would provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "tasklist",
      "net use",
      "diskpart",
      "netstat"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "net use The net use command will assign a local drive letter to a network share. Once the net use command is completed, the drive letter can be used to reference the share in all applications and in the File Explorer. The incorrect answers: A. tasklist The tasklist command will display a list of all running processes in the operating system. The tasklist command will not associate a drive letter with a Windows share. C. diskpart The diskpart command is used to manage disk configurations, partitions, and volumes. The diskpart command is not used for drive letters and shares. D. netstat The netstat utility will display network statistics relating to active connections, application usage, and network activity. The netstat command does not associate drive letters with Windows shares. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.2 The Windows Network Command Line https://professormesser.link/1102010202 Practice Exam B - Answers 173",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B8"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "A macOS server administrator needs a backup system to allow the recovery of data from any point in the last thirty days. Which of the following should be used for this requirement?",
    "options": [
      "Backup and Restore",
      "Remote Disc",
      "Spaces",
      "Time Machine"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Time Machine The backup utility included with macOS is called Time Machine. Time Machine will create backups automatically and maintain as many days as the backup media's free space can store. The incorrect answers: A. Backup and Restore The Windows backup utility is called Backup and Restore. These backups are not compatible with the macOS operating system. B. Remote Disc Remote Disc allows other macOS devices to use an optical drive from another computer across the network. This is designed for copying files and will not work with audio CDs or video DVDs. Remote Disc does not provide a method for backing up macOS data. C. Spaces The Spaces utility can be used in macOS to create multiple desktops and separate work \"spaces\" that can be used independently of each other. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.10 - macOS System Preferences https://professormesser.link/1102011002 174 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B9"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "A desktop administrator is upgrading an older computer to support the 64-bit version of Windows 10 Pro. The computer currently has: 1 GHz CPU 1 GB of RAM 50 GB of free storage space 1024 x 768 video resolution Which of the following should be upgraded to support the Windows 10 installation?",
    "options": [
      "CPU",
      "RAM",
      "Storage space",
      "Video resolution"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "RAM The 64-bit version of all Windows 10 editions require a minimum of 2 GB of system memory. Since this system only has 1 GB of RAM, it will need a memory upgrade before Windows 10 x64 can be installed. The incorrect answers: A. CPU A processor running at 1 GHz is supported by both the 32-bit and 64-bit versions of Windows 10. C. Storage space The 64-bit version of Windows 10 requires 32 GB of free disk space. This system has 50 GB of free storage space, so it can easily support an upgrade to Windows 10 Pro x64. D. Video resolution Windows 10 Pro x64 requires a video resolution of 800 x 600, and this system supports a resolution of 1024 x 768 pixels. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.1 - Windows Features https://professormesser.link/1102010102 176 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B11"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "A system administrator has been tasked with locating all of the log files contained within an application folder. The folder currently contains over a thousand files, and only a portion of them have a .log extension. Which of these Windows commands would be the BEST way to find these files?",
    "options": [
      "sfc",
      "diskpart",
      "robocopy",
      "dir"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "dir The dir (directory) command will display a list of files from the command line. The command includes filtering options, so using \"dir *.log\" would display all files in the current directory with a .log extension. The incorrect answers: A. sfc The sfc (System File Checker) command will scan the integrity of all protected system files and correct any files that may have been changed since their installation. The sfc command will not display a list of files in the current directory. B. diskpart The diskpart command is a command line utility for viewing and managing volumes on a Windows device. The diskpart command does not provide file management. C. robocopy The robocopy (Robust Copy) command provides additional features over the copy or xcopy commands. The robocopy utility does not provide the file management features required to search and delete certain files in a directory. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.2 - Windows Command Line Tools https://professormesser.link/1102010201 178 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B13"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "A system administrator is analyzing a problem with a USB flash drive on a Windows 10 computer. When the flash drive is inserted, the CPU utilization increases to 100%. The administrator would like to disable one of the computer’s USB controllers for troubleshooting. Which of the following would provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "Services",
      "Performance Monitor",
      "Event Viewer",
      "Device Manager"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Device Manager The Windows Device Manager provides access to the device drivers that manage the hardware on a computer. Individual drivers can be enabled, disabled, and managed from the Device Manager utility. The incorrect answers: A. Services The Services utility manages background service processes in Windows. The Services utility does not manage or disable hardware components. B. Performance Monitor The Performance Monitor gathers long-term statistics and can alert or create reports for ongoing performance metrics. Performance Monitor does not manage hardware device drivers. C. Event Viewer The Event Viewer contains logs from the applications, operating system, and other services. Although the Event Viewer may provide additional details about this flash drive issue, the administrator would not manage the device drivers from the Event Viewer utility. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 180 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B15"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "Which of the following features would be found in Windows 10 Pro but not in Windows 10 Home?",
    "options": [
      "32-bit and 64-bit versions",
      "Domain access",
      "RDP client",
      "Windows Workgroup"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Domain access Windows 10 Home does not include any access or connectivity to a Windows Domain. The incorrect answers: A. 32-bit and 64-bit versions Windows 10 includes both 32-bit and 64-bit options when performing an installation. These versions are available for all editions of Windows 10. C. RDP client An RDP (Remote Desktop Protocol) client is used to connect to an RDP service on another device. All editions of Windows and many non-Windows platforms can use some type of RDP client. D. Windows Workgroup A Windows Workgroup is the fundamental networking available in Windows, and it's most often implemented in a home environment. All editions of Windows support connecting to a Windows Workgroup. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.1 - Windows Features https://professormesser.link/1102010102 184 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B19"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": "A security administrator has been asked to reinstall Windows on a web server diagnosed with a rootkit infection. Which of the following installation methods would be the BEST choice for this server?",
    "options": [
      "In-place upgrade",
      "Remote network installation",
      "Clean install",
      "Repair installation"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Clean install A clean install would be the best way to guarantee the removal of any malware. Leaving any portion of the operating system in place could potentially leave malware on the system. The incorrect answers: A. In-place upgrade An in-place upgrade would change the operating system to a different version and would potentially leave malware running on the newly upgraded OS. B. Remote network installation Since this computer has been diagnosed with malware, it would not be a good best practice to reconnect the server to the network. D. Repair installation A repair installation is designed to fix problems with the operating system, and it does not commonly remove any malware or rootkits. The only way to guarantee the removal of malware is to delete everything and reinstall or restore from a known good backup. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 Practice Exam B - Answers 191",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B26"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "A desktop administrator is troubleshooting an older computer that has been slowing down as more applications and files are stored on the hard drive. Which of the following commands would be the BEST choice for increasing the performance of this computer?",
    "options": [
      "defrag",
      "format",
      "sfc",
      "xcopy",
      "winver"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "defrag As files are stored on a hard drive, the files can be fragmented and stored on different parts of the drive. The defragmentation utility moves the file fragments so they are contiguous, and this process improves the overall read and write times. The incorrect answers: B. format The format command is used to initialize a file system. Running the format command would remove all of the information on the partition. C. sfc The sfc (System File Checker) utility will scan all protected system files and replace any files that may have changed since their installation. D. xcopy The xcopy (Extended Copy) command is used to copy files and directories at the command prompt. The xcopy command does not provide any performance enhancements. E. winver The winver (Windows Version) command will display the Windows version dialog on the desktop. The winver command doesn't provide any changes to the operating system performance. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.2 - Windows Command Line Tools https://professormesser.link/1102010201 198 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B33"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "A technician has created a Windows image that can be used across all of the computers in a test lab. Which of the following would be the best way to deploy these images?",
    "options": [
      "Clean install",
      "Remote network installation",
      "Repair installation",
      "Remote Disc"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Remote network installation When installing images to multiple systems, it's more efficient to use the network as a distribution method. This process allows for multiple installations to occur simultaneously without any type of human intervention. The incorrect answers: A. Clean install A clean install requires separate installation media for each computer, so a room of thirty training computer will also require thirty separate installation boot media. PXE is a much more efficient method than using separate media. C. Repair installation A repair installation will overwrite an existing operating system with the same version. A repair installation does not use an image to reinstall the operating system. D. Remote Disc Remote Disc is a utility for sharing data CDs and DVDs on the macOS operating system. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 202 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B36"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "Which of the following partition types limit a Windows installation to a maximum partition size of 2 TB?",
    "options": [
      "FAT32",
      "GPT",
      "APFS",
      "MBR"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "MBR The MBR (Master Boot Record) partition style is an older method partitioning files, and the maximum partition size of an MBR partition is two terabytes in size. The incorrect answers: A. FAT32 FAT32 (File Allocation Table 32-bit) is a Microsoft file system originally designed for earlier versions of Windows. FAT32 is not a partition type. B. GPT GPT (GUID Partition Table) is a modern partition style that increases the number of partitions and partition sizes over the older MBR style. C. APFS Apple's APFS (Apple File System) is optimized for solid-state storage and includes support for encryption, snapshots, and increased data integrity. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.8 - File Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010802 208 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B42"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "A server administrator is installing a 4 TB drive in a database server and would like to use all free space as a single partition. Which of the following technologies should be used with this drive?",
    "options": [
      "FAT32",
      "MBR",
      "Active Directory",
      "GPT"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "GPT The GPT (GUID Partition Table) partition style provides for very large partition sizes. GPT would easily allow a single partition of 4 terabytes. The incorrect answers: A. FAT32 The FAT32 (File Allocation Table 32-bit) file system limits volume sizes to a maximum of 2 TB. B. MBR The MBR (Master Boot Record) partition style does not allow the creation of partitions greater than 2 TB. C. Active Directory Active Directory provides large-scale management of devices across the enterprise from a single console. Active Directory is not related to the size or available storage space on a drive. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 Practice Exam B - Answers 211",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B45"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "A system administrator needs to modify a file in the \\Windows\\Installer directory, but the folder doesn’t appear in the file list. Which of these options would help the system administrator with this task?",
    "options": [
      "Safe Mode",
      "File Explorer Options",
      "User Accounts",
      "Internet Options"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "File Explorer Options The File Explorer commonly hides operating system files. Un-checking the \"Hide protected operating system files (Recommended)\" would display the files to the system administrator. The incorrect answers: A. Safe Mode Safe Mode is useful when troubleshooting operating system problems, but it will not change the files displayed in Windows File Explorer. C. User Accounts The User Accounts Control Panel applet can be used to create or modify existing accounts. The User Accounts options do not include the ability to display or hide certain file types. D. Internet Options The Internet Options configuration can be used to modify the connectivity options available when using a browser. These options will not enable or disable the display of certain file types. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Control Panel https://professormesser.link/1102010401 214 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B48"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "A Linux administrator is modifying a log file and needs to rename the file. Which of the following should be used to make this change?",
    "options": [
      "rm",
      "mv",
      "mkdir",
      "pwd"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "mv The Linux mv (move) command will move a file from one location to another, or move/rename a file from one name to another. The incorrect answers: A. rm The Linux rm (remove) command will delete a file or object from the file system. C. mkdir The mkdir (Make Directory) command can be used in Linux or Windows to create a folder or directory in the file system. D. pwd The Linux pwd (Print Working Directory) command will display the path of the current working directory. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.11 - Linux Commands https://professormesser.link/1102011101 Practice Exam B - Answers 215",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B49"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "A technician would like to modify a configuration in a user's UEFI BIOS, but the system will not provide a BIOS configuration hotkey after shutting down and powering on the computer. Which of the following would be the BEST way to address this issue?",
    "options": [
      "Change the File Explorer Options",
      "Modify the Indexing Options",
      "Turn off Fast Startup",
      "Start the computer in Safe Mode",
      "Modify the Ease of Access settings"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Turn off Fast Startup Fast Startup can bypass many of the normal startup options, so using the Control Panel Power options for disabling Fast Startup can allow a technician to regain access to the BIOS startup hotkeys. The incorrect answers: A. Change the File Explorer Options There are options in the Control Panel to modify File Explorer options, but none of those options would provide access to the BIOS startup keys. B. Modify the Indexing Options The Indexing Options specify which folders should be used during the Windows search process. Modifying the Indexing Options will not allow access to the BIOS startup options. D. Start the computer in Safe Mode Starting the computer with Safe Mode would help troubleshoot any ongoing Windows issues, but it would not provide any access to the BIOS configuration. E. Modify the Ease of Access settings The Control Panel's Ease of Access settings allow the user to make the computer easier to use, but it doesn't change any of the startup or BIOS configuration options. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Control Panel https://professormesser.link/1102010401 Practice Exam B - Answers 219",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B53"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "A user on the sales team has opened a help desk ticket because of short battery times on a new company-provided tablet. When using the tablet, the battery only lasts a few hours before shutting off. Which of the following would be the BEST choices for improving the battery life? (Select TWO)",
    "options": [
      "Install the latest operating system patches",
      "Increase the brightness levels",
      "Connect to the corporate VPN",
      "Disable Bluetooth and cellular connections",
      "Close apps that work in the background",
      "Perform a soft reset The Answers: D. Disable Bluetooth and cellular connections, and",
      "Close apps that work in the background The two options that would have the largest power savings would disable wireless Bluetooth radios and close applications that use CPU power. The incorrect answers:",
      "Install the latest operating system patches Installing operating system patches do not commonly resolve issues with excessive battery usage. After installing the patches, the battery use would most likely remain the same.",
      "Increase the brightness levels Increasing brightness levels would have the opposite of the intended effect, since additional battery will be required by the brighter display.",
      "Connect to the corporate VPN Connecting to the corporate VPN (Virtual Private Network) would require additional wireless communication and increased CPU usage due to the encryption and decryption process used by the VPN.",
      "Perform a soft reset Performing a soft reset might help if the issue was associated with a problematic application or unusual system state. There's no evidence that either of these is occurring, so resetting the system would most likely have no effect on the battery life. More information: 220-1102, Objective 3.4 - Troubleshooting Mobile Devices https://professormesser.link/1102030401 Practice Exam B - Answers 223 B58. A system administrator would like to perform a Windows installation while users are away from their desks. Which of the following would be the BEST option for this installation?",
      "Remote network installation",
      "Recovery partition installation",
      "Repair installation",
      "In-place upgrade"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Remote network installation A remote network installation can install the Windows files from a centralized network server and multiple devices can be installed simultaneously. A remote network installation is a common option in a workplace with many Windows devices. The incorrect answers: B. Recovery partition installation A recovery partition can be a good installation option, but it requires the partition to previously exist on the system. The recovery partition may not be available on all systems. C. Repair installation A repair installation will overwrite an existing installation with the same version of the operating system to potentially repair problems with the existing installation. A repair installation does not imply that the installation would be performed without user intervention. D. In-place upgrade An in-place upgrade will leave user documents and configurations in place during the upgrade process. An in-place upgrade requires user intervention by default. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 224 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B57"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "A user in the accounting department has installed a new application for the upcoming tax year. Although the current application worked perfectly, the newer application runs significantly slower. Which of the following should be the FIRST troubleshooting step?",
    "options": [
      "Roll back to the previous application",
      "Run a repair installation",
      "Verify the requirements for the new application",
      "Perform a system file check The Answers: C. Verify the requirements for the new application The new application may not have the same requirements as the older application, so the user's computer may require additional CPU, memory, or storage space. The incorrect answers:",
      "Roll back to the previous application The previous application may work properly, but it's designed for a different tax year. The new tax year will require an updated application.",
      "Run a repair installation A repair installation can often resolve issues with the Windows operating system, but this question doesn't clearly point to any OS issues. Running a repair installation would not be the first step in the troubleshooting process.",
      "Perform a system file check The Windows System File Checker (SFC) utility can scan the operating system for modified files and correct any inconsistencies. However, this question doesn't clearly show any operating system issues, so running an SFC scan would not be the first step when troubleshooting. More information: 220-1102, Objective 3.1 - Troubleshooting Solutions https://professormesser.link/1102030102 Practice Exam B - Answers 225 B60. A macOS user needs encrypt all of the information on their laptop. Which of the following would be the BEST choice for this requirement?",
      "Spaces",
      "Remote Disc",
      "FileVault",
      "Keychain"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "FileVault The FileVault utility provides full disk encryption for macOS devices. The incorrect answers: A. Spaces Spaces allows a user to configured multiple macOS desktops on the screen. The Spaces feature does not allow the macOS desktop to run Windows applications. B. Remote Disc Remote Disc allows a macOS user to share the optical drive of another computer on the network. Remote Disc does not provide a method of running Windows applications. D. Keychain The macOS Keychain utility maintains and secures passwords, notes, certificates, and other private information. The Keychain does not More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.10 - macOS Features https://professormesser.link/1102011003 226 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B59"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "An administrator is troubleshooting an error message that appears each time an application is started. The administrator has uninstalled and reinstalled the application, but the error message still appears. Which of the following would be the BEST next troubleshooting step?",
    "options": [
      "Use Performance Manager to monitor the system",
      "Check the Event Viewer logs",
      "View the hardware settings in Device Manager",
      "Disable unneeded background processes in Services"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Check the Event Viewer logs The Windows Event Viewer can provide extensive information about the operating system and the applications. Error messages and application failures are logged in the Event Viewer for review. The incorrect answers: A. Use Performance Manager to monitor the system Performance Manager provides long-term views of system metrics such as CPU, memory, and network resource usage. Performance Manager is not used to monitor application failures. C. View the hardware settings in Device Manager The Device Manager can view and manage the hardware on a Windows computer. The Device Manager does not track application problems. D. Disable unneeded background processes in Services Although a Windows Service may be the root cause of this issue, we don't have enough information to make that determination. Instead of guessing at an issue, it would be a more directed and efficient process to gather information on the actual error using Windows Event Viewer. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 232 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B66"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "Which of these describes a free, open-source operating system?",
    "options": [
      "macOS",
      "Linux",
      "Windows",
      "iOS"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Linux The Linux operating system has become popular through the development in the open source community and free distribution of the operating system software. The incorrect answers: A. macOS The macOS operating system is an Apple product and is not available as open source. Although the price of macOS is minimal, it is still not a free operating system. C. Windows The Windows operating system is a closed-source product from Microsoft. Windows is not distributed as a free operating system. D. iOS Apple's iOS is their closed-source mobile operating system for smartphones. iOS is included with the mobile hardware provided by Apple. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.8 - Operating Systems Overview https://professormesser.link/1102010801 Practice Exam B - Answers 235",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B69"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "A system administrator has installed a SOHO network of five Windows computers. The administrator would like to provide a method of sharing documents and spreadsheets between all of the office computers. Which of the following would be the BEST way to provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "Domain",
      "Proxy server",
      "Workgroup",
      "Remote Desktop"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Workgroup A Windows Workgroup is a common sharing method for small departments with documents on their own computers. The incorrect answers: A. Domain Microsoft's Active Directory Domain Services are designed for larger organizations that need centralized management of user accounts, computing devices, and servers. B. Proxy server A proxy server is used to secure and control network communication. A proxy server is not used for sharing documents in an office. D. Remote Desktop The Remote Desktop feature in Windows allows a device to view and control the screen of another computer. Remote Desktop functionality is not used for sharing files. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.6 - Windows Network Technologies https://professormesser.link/1102010601 Practice Exam B - Answers 239",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B73"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "A system administrator needs to configure a laptop to support inbound Remote Desktop services for the help desk team. Which of these Control Panel features provides access to these settings?",
    "options": [
      "Internet Options",
      "Devices and Printers",
      "Network and Sharing Center",
      "System"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "System The System utility includes a Remote tab for Remote Assistance and Remote Desktop. The Remote Desktop option is available in non-Home editions of Windows. The incorrect answers: A. Internet Properties The Internet Properties utility includes configuration options for the browser and configuration settings for proxies. B. Devices and Printers The Devices and Printers utility allows for the addition, removal, or configuration of monitors, storage drivers, printers, and more. C. Network and Sharing Center The Network and Sharing Center provides access to network configurations, file sharing options, and other network-related configurations. The options for Remote Desktop are not located in the Network and Sharing Center. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Control Panel https://professormesser.link/1102010401 Practice Exam B - Answers 245",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B79"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "A system administrator is installing a new video editing application on a user’s workstation from an installation USB flash drive. However, the installation process fails due to lack of available drive space. Which of the following would be the BEST way to complete the installation process?",
    "options": [
      "Use a share drive for the installation source",
      "Compress the installation files",
      "Install the application to a network share",
      "Manually copy the installation files to the application directory"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Install the application to a network share The installed application files can be much larger than the installation utility, so using a network share with a larger available storage space can be a good alternative until free space is available on the local computer. The incorrect answers: A. Use a share drive for the installation source Changing the installation media from a USB (Universal Serial Bus) drive to a share drive would not provide any additional free space on the destination storage drive. B. Compress the installation files Most installation files are already compressed, but compressing files on the installation media would not provide additional free space on the application storage drive. D. Manually copy the installation files to the application directory Most installation programs do not simply copy the existing files to a directory. The installation program often uncompresses the files, updates registry settings, and updates Windows configurations. Manually copying the files would not result in a properly installed application, and it would not provide any additional free space for the installation. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.7 - Installing Applications https://professormesser.link/1102010701 248 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B82"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "A system administrator is troubleshooting an application issue. The application uses an increasing amount of memory until all available RAM is eventually depleted. The computer must be rebooted every few days when this memory issue occurs. Which of the following utilities would show how much RAM is used by this application?",
    "options": [
      "Event Viewer",
      "Device Manager",
      "Task Manager",
      "Programs and Features"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Task Manager Task Manager provides a real-time view of system metrics, including CPU utilization, storage use, and memory utilization. The incorrect answers: A. Event Viewer The Windows Event Viewer is a consolidated log of all system events. Real-time memory usage is not monitored by the Event Viewer. B. Device Manager The Device Manager provides management of the hardware device drivers. Resource utilization and memory information is not provided in Device Manager. D. Programs and Features Applications and Windows features can be installed or removed from the Programs and Features applet. Programs and Features does not display memory utilization statistics. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 - Task Manager https://professormesser.link/1102010301 250 Practice Exam B - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B84"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "A desktop administrator is troubleshooting an error that randomly causes a workstation to spike to 100% utilization. Which of these utilities would help the administrator track and report on system utilization over a 24-hour period?",
    "options": [
      "Performance Monitor",
      "Device Manager",
      "Services",
      "Task Scheduler"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Performance Monitor The Windows Performance Monitor can track and store long-term information on many different system resources, including CPU, memory, network performance, and more. The incorrect answers: B. Device Manager The Device Manager is the central management utility for hardware device drivers. Device Manager does not provide a way to track system utilization over time. C. Services The Services applet will allow the administrator to view and control the background services on a Windows computer. The Services utility will not display system utilization over time. D. Task Scheduler The Windows Task Scheduler will run scripts and applications on certain dates and times. Task Scheduler does not gather performance metrics. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 Practice Exam B - Answers 255",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "B89"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "A system administrator would like to remove the TFTP Client in Windows 10. Which of the following Control Panel options would be the BEST choice for this task?",
    "options": [
      "Programs and Features",
      "Services",
      "Network and Sharing Center",
      "File Explorer options"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Programs and Features The Programs and Features option of the Control Panel is used to view and manage installed applications, or to enable or disable individual Windows features. The incorrect answers: B. Services The Services utility would allow the administrator to disable a TFTP service, or any other Windows service. To remove a client or Windows feature, the administrator would need to use Programs and Features. C. Network and Sharing Center The Network and Sharing Center manages all network adapters and sharing settings in Windows. The Network and Sharing Center does not enable or disable individual application use. D. File Explorer options The File Explorer options are used to customize the options available in the File Explorer, change the view in the window, and modify the Windows search options. File Explorer does not control the use of individual applications. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Control Panel https://professormesser.link/1102010401 300 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C7"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "A computer technician has been asked to verify a set of new Group Policy settings on computers at a remote site. Which of the following commands should be used to validate the last policy update on the systems?",
    "options": [
      "net use",
      "sfc",
      "gpresult",
      "netstat",
      "tracert"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "gpresult The gpresult (Group Policy Results) utility will display the policy settings associated with a computer or user. The incorrect answers: A. net use The net use command can be used to assign a drive letter to a network share. The net use command will not display Group Policy information. B. sfc The sfc (System File Checker) command will scan the integrity of all protected system files and repair any that may be damaged. D. netstat The netstat (Network Statistics) command can display active connections, routing tables, and other network traffic metrics. The netstat command is not associated with Group Policy settings. E. tracert The tracert (traceroute) command can be used to build a list of routes between IP subnets. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.2 - Windows Command Line Tools https://professormesser.link/1102010201 Practice Exam C - Answers 303",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C10"
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "A system administrator needs to modify the Linux group associated with a file. Which of the following would provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "ps",
      "df",
      "chown",
      "grep"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "chown The chown (Change Owner) command will modify the owner or group associated with a file system object. The incorrect answers: A. ps The ps (List Processes) command will display a list of the running processes on a Linux computer. The ps command does not display group information relating to a file. B. df The df (Disk Free) command displays the Linux file systems and the available and used space on each file system. D. grep The grep command is used to find text in a file. Many files can be searched simultaneously, and the resulting matches are displayed to the Linux console. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.11 - Linux Commands https://professormesser.link/1102011101 304 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C11"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "A system administrator is concerned about the security of devices in the field and would like to encrypt all data on company laptops. Which of these Windows features would provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "EFS",
      "Domain Services",
      "WPA3",
      "BitLocker"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "BitLocker BitLocker is a Windows feature providing full disk encryption of entire volumes. All data stored on a BitLocker-enabled laptop is encrypted by default. The incorrect answers: A. EFS EFS (Encrypting File System) is a feature that encrypts file system objects on a Windows computer. EFS does not generally provide encryption of all files on a storage drive or volume. B. Domain Services Domain Services describes a centralized management function of the Windows operating system. Larger networks use Domain Services to easily manage all of the Windows systems on the network. C. WPA3 WPA3 is a wireless security protocol and does not provide any security for data stored on a laptop. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.1 - Windows Features https://professormesser.link/1102010102 308 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C15"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "The available storage space on a user’s workstation is running low, and some updates are failing due to insufficient drive space. Which of the following would be the BEST way to increase drive space until a larger storage drive can be installed?",
    "options": [
      "Use a Guest login",
      "Enable System Protection",
      "Disable the internal Ethernet interface",
      "Set the paging file size to zero"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Set the paging file size to zero The paging file is used with your system RAM to keep the applications performing at peak efficiency. Although disabling the paging file may affect the performance of a computer, it will free up all of the storage space that's normally reserved for the swap file. The incorrect answers: A. Use a Guest login The type of login used on a computer does not generally affect the amount of free storage space on the computer. B. Enable System Protection The Windows System Protection feature will set restore points and save files and configurations to the storage drive. Enabling this feature will use more storage space, not less. C. Disable the internal Ethernet interface Modifying the status of the Ethernet connection does not affect the available storage space on the computer. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Control Panel https://professormesser.link/1102010401 310 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C17"
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "A technician is troubleshooting a Windows 10 computer performing very slowly when moving from one application to another. Which of the following utilities would allow the technician to view real-time resource activity?",
    "options": [
      "Services",
      "Task Manager",
      "System Information",
      "Device Manager"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Task Manager The Windows Task Manager provides a real-time view of CPU utilization, memory usage, network throughput, and more. The incorrect answers: A. Services The Services utility allows the administrator to enable, disable, and configure non-interactive Windows Services. The Services utility does not show real-time performance information. C. System Information The System Information utility displays hardware resource configurations, component details, and software information. The System Information utility does not provide a real-time view of performance metrics. D. Device Manager The Device Manager is the central console for managing all hardware device drivers. The Device Manager does not provide any information on real-time system performance. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 - Task Manager https://professormesser.link/1102010301 Practice Exam C - Answers 311",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C18"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "A server administrator needs to create a folder on a Windows server to store weekly status report documents. Which of the following command- line tools would provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "md",
      "net use",
      "cd",
      "dir",
      "ls"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "md The md (Make Directory) command is used to create a subdirectory or folder on the file system. The incorrect answers: B. net use The net command is used for many different Windows-related functions. The net use option will associate a drive letter with a Windows share. C. cd The cd (Change Directory) command is used to change the current command line context to a different working directory. The cd command is used in both Windows and Linux. D. dir The Windows dir (Directory) command is used to provide a list of the files and objects in the file system. E. ls The ls (list directory) command is used to view the files and objects in the Linux file system. This is the Linux equivalent of the Windows dir command. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.2 - Windows Command Line Tools https://professormesser.link/1102010201 Practice Exam C - Answers 313",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C20"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "A Windows 10 computer is displaying a series of error messages during the startup process. A technician has been dispatched and would like to view more information about the errors without restarting the computer. Which of the following utilities would provide the technician with more details?",
    "options": [
      "taskschd",
      "devmgmt",
      "perfmon",
      "eventvwr",
      "sfc"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "eventvwr The Windows eventvwr (Event Viewer) utility provides a historical log of all system and application events. The error messages seen previously on the system can be found in the Event viewer. The incorrect answers: A. taskschd The taskschd (Task Scheduler) feature is used to automate a task at a specific date and time. This allows the user to update the system, download files, or perform any other function without any user intervention. B. devmgmt The Windows devmgmt (Device Manager) utility provides access to the hardware device drivers. C. perfmon The perfmon (Performance Monitor) feature gathers performance metrics over time to provide a graphical view of trends. E. sfc The sfc (System File Checker) utility will scan the integrity of protected system files and repair files that may be corrupted. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 316 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C23"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "A desktop technician has received a complaint that a remotely-hosted application has stopped working. The technician believes that a network outage at the application provider is the root cause of the issue. Which of the following tools would be the BEST choice to confirm the location of the outage?",
    "options": [
      "ping",
      "nslookup",
      "netstat",
      "tracert"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "tracert The tracert (traceroute) utility will show the network routes between two devices. If the route is disrupted between those two devices, the last available router will be identified. The incorrect answers: A. ping The ping command will identify devices on the network, but it does not provide any location details if the device does not respond. B. nslookup The nslookup (Name Server Lookup) command will query a DNS (Domain Name System) server to identify IP addresses and fully qualified domain names. The nslookup command does not provide any information about network traffic or outages. C. netstat The netstat command will display connections, routes, and other network statistics associated with a single device. The netstat command does not provide any information about the uptime and availability of a remote network connection. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.4 - The Windows Network Command Line https://professormesser.link/1102010202 Practice Exam C - Answers 321",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C28"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "A Linux administrator is using the grep command while monitoring a database application. Which of the following would BEST describe this activity?",
    "options": [
      "Search through a file for specific text",
      "View a list of running processes",
      "Change the permissions of a file",
      "View the name of the working directory"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Search through a file for specific text The grep command is used to search through a file or set of files for specific text. The incorrect answers: B. View of list of running processes The ps (Process List) command is commonly used to view all of the running processes on a Linux computer. This is similar in functionality to the Windows Task Manager. C. Change the permissions of a file The Linux chmod (Change Mode) command is used to change the permissions of a file for the file owner, the file group, and everyone else. D. View the name of the working directory The pwd (Print Working Directory) command is used to display the current working directory path. This command is the same in both Windows and Linux. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.11 - Linux Commands https://professormesser.link/1102011101 324 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C31"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "A system administrator would like to upgrade a user's Windows video editing application to the latest version, but the upgrade utility fails with the error \"Not enough free space.\" Which of the following utilities would allow the system administrator to resolve this issue?",
    "options": [
      "cleanmgr",
      "perfmon",
      "eventvwr",
      "taskschd",
      "diskmgmt"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "cleanmgr The cleanmgr.exe (Disk Cleanup) utility will find unused or unneeded files and remove them from the file system. This might include temporary Internet files, error reports, downloaded program files, and others. The incorrect answers: B. perfmon The perfmon.msc (Performance Monitor) utility displays long-term graphs and collects data regarding CPU, network, memory, and other system resources. C. eventvwr The eventvwr.msc (Event Viewer) utility provides a log of all operating system, application, and security events in Microsoft Windows. D. taskschd The Windows taskschd.msc (Task Scheduler) allow the scheduling of an application or script. E. diskmgmt Disk operations can be managed through the diskmgmt.msc (Disk Management) utility. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 - Additional Windows Tools https://professormesser.link/1102010303 Practice Exam C - Answers 331",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C38"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "A Windows administrator needs to define a minimum password length for all network users. Which of the following should be used to complete this task?",
    "options": [
      "Device Manager",
      "Certificate Manager",
      "Group Policy Editor",
      "Performance Monitor"
    ],
    "correct": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Group Policy Editor The Group Policy Editor works in conjunction with Active Directory services to manage almost any aspect of a client system. The incorrect answers: A. Device Manager The Windows Device Manager is used to enable, disable, and configure hardware device drivers in the operating system. B. Certificate Manager The Certificate Manager is a centralized certificate store for root certificates, trusted publishers, trusted people, and more. D. Performance Monitor Performance Monitor gathers long-term statistics and performance metrics from the operating system. Performance monitor will not manage security policies on a system. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.3 The Microsoft Management Console https://professormesser.link/1102010302 Practice Exam C - Answers 335",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C42"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "A manager in the accounting department would like to upgrade to Windows 10, but she doesn’t want to lose access to any of the currently installed applications or data. Which of the following methods would be the BEST choice for these requirements?",
    "options": [
      "Clean install",
      "Image deployment",
      "Remote network installation",
      "In-place upgrade"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "In-place upgrade An in-place upgrade keeps all of the existing data, applications, and configurations in place during the upgrade process. The incorrect answers: A. Clean install A clean install removes all data from a system. After a clean install is complete, the user would need to restore their data files from backup and reinstall all of their applications. B. Image deployment An image deployment is a pre-built version of Windows. This image may not include all required applications, and no user data would be contained in an image deployment. C. Remote network installation An installation occurring over the network is often done to simplify the process and avoid the need for each workstation to use boot media. A network installation doesn't necessarily mean that an in-place upgrade is occurring. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 Practice Exam C - Answers 339",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C46"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "A help desk is receiving reports that a group of devices is not able to communicate outside of their local IP subnet. A technician can ping devices on the same network, but does not receive a response when pinging the IP address of external devices. Which of the following would be the MOST likely cause of this issue?",
    "options": [
      "Default gateway",
      "DNS server",
      "Proxy server",
      "Metered connection"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Default gateway The default gateway is the router providing the communication between the local IP subnet and the rest of the world. If the default gateway isn't working, users will not be able to access services that are outside of the local subnet. The incorrect answers: B. DNS server The DNS server converts between a fully qualified domain name and an IP address. In this example, the technician was attempting to ping external devices by IP address, so the DNS server would not be part of this issue. C. Proxy server A proxy server is commonly used to provide security for incoming or outgoing web services. A technician pinging an external IP address would not commonly be communicating through a proxy server. D. Metered connection A metered connection will limit the type and amount of traffic sent over a network connection. Since the pings are working for one device, it's safe to assume the network connections are not metered or restricted. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.6 - Windows IP Address Configuration https://professormesser.link/1102010603 Practice Exam C - Answers 341",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C48"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "A user is working with a .dmg file on their macOS desktop. Which of the following would describe the contents of this file?",
    "options": [
      "Debug information",
      "Disk image",
      "Application library",
      "Disk maintenance utility"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Disk image The macOS equivalent to an ISO file is a DMG (Disk Image) file. Disk images can be created and managed from the macOS Disk Utility. The incorrect answers: A. Debug information Debug information is commonly available in the macOS console or directly from an application. A .dmg file is not a container of debug information. C. Application library Application library files in macOS are used to contain back-end configurations, framework classes, and other important application files. These files are often stored in the Library folder in macOS. The .dmg file is not used to store application library files. D. Disk maintenance utility The macOS Disk Utility can be used to create and manage .dmg files, but the disk maintenance utility would not necessarily be contained within a .dmg file. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.10 - macOS Overview https://professormesser.link/1102011001 352 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C59"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "A user would like to configure their local printer to be accessible to anyone on the corporate network. Which of the following would be the BEST way to configure this connection?",
    "options": [
      "Configure a VPN connection",
      "Create a share name in printer properties",
      "Configure a metered connection",
      "Use a static IP address"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Create a share name in printer properties The printer properties includes a sharing tab with the option to \"Share this printer\" and to create the name for the printer share. The incorrect answers: A. Configure a VPN connection A VPN (Virtual Private Network) creates an encrypted tunnel between two devices or locations. In this example, the printer is used on the internal corporate network so a VPN would not be required. C. Configure a metered connection Metered connections are commonly used to reduce data usage, especially over slow or costly links. A metered connection would not be required to share a printer on the corporate network. D. Use a static IP address Windows networking does not require a static IP address to share files or printers. Most organizations will use dynamic addressing for all of the user devices. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.6 - Windows Network Technologies https://professormesser.link/1102010601 358 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C64"
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "A user in the marketing department needs to move data between macOS and Windows computers using a USB flash drive. Which of the following file systems would be the BEST way to easily transfer files between these operating systems?",
    "options": [
      "exFAT",
      "APFS",
      "NTFS",
      "ext4"
    ],
    "correct": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "exFAT The exFAT (Extended File Allocation Table) file system is designed for flash drives and can be used across Windows, Linux, macOS, and other operating systems. The incorrect answers: B. APFS APFS (Apple File System) is used exclusively on macOS and other Apple devices. A flash drive formatted with APFS would not be accessible from the Windows operating system. C. NTFS The NTFS (NT File System) file system is the standard for Windows devices. Although it can be read by macOS, it is not completely compatible with the macOS operating system. D. ext4 The ext4 (Fourth Extended Filesystem) is commonly associated with Linux and Android operating systems. A USB drive formatted with ext4 would not be the best way to transfer files between Windows and macOS. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.8 - File Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010802 360 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C66"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "A workstation technician manages a training center with thirty student computers in each room. All of the computers have the same hardware configurations. Which of these installation methods would be the BEST choice for quickly resetting the training rooms at the end of each week?",
    "options": [
      "In-place upgrade",
      "Image installation",
      "Repair installation",
      "Clean install"
    ],
    "correct": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Image installation An image installation can install an operating system, applications, and customized system configurations to multiple devices in a single step. With a pre-built images, a large training room of systems can be updated with a specific configuration very efficiently. The incorrect answers: A. In-place upgrade An in-place upgrade will modify the version of Windows running on a system. In this example, the systems need to be reset to their original state. C. Repair installation A repair installation is used to fix an installation that cannot boot properly to a Windows desktop. The repair installation will attempt to repair portions of the startup process, but it will not modify the user's files or applications. D. Clean install A clean install would provide a fresh starting point, but it doesn't include any of the applications required for the training facility. Most systems will require additional configurations and application installations after a clean install. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.9 - Installing Operating Systems https://professormesser.link/1102010901 Practice Exam C - Answers 363",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C69"
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "A user has purchased a computer that uses a 32-bit version of an operating system. Which of the following would be the maximum amount of RAM supported in this OS?",
    "options": [
      "Disable guest account",
      "Enable file storage quotas",
      "Enable password complexity The Answers: D. Disable guest account, and",
      "Enable password complexity The only available options associated with server security are those to disable guest accounts and increase the complexity of the passwords. Guest accounts can be exploited, and passwords that are easy to guess or set to defaults can be discovered by an attacker. The incorrect answers:",
      "Enable a BIOS user password Enabling a password during the startup process does not protect the server once it has started.",
      "Connect the server to a wireless network Wireless networks do not provide any additional application security. Connecting to a wireless network would not improve the security posture of the server.",
      "Limit the number of concurrent connections Limiting concurrent connections would restrict the throughput of the service and would not provide any security enhancements.",
      "Enable file storage quotas Storage quotas would conserve storage space on the server, but they would not provide any additional security enhancements. More information: 220-1102, Objective 2.6 - Security Best Practices https://professormesser.link/1102020601 368 Practice Exam C - Answers C75. A user has purchased a computer that uses a 32-bit version of an operating system. Which of the following would be the maximum amount of RAM supported in this OS?",
      "32 GB",
      "2 TB",
      "512 GB",
      "128 GB",
      "4 GB",
      "16 GB"
    ],
    "correct": [
      4
    ],
    "explanation": "4 GB A 32-bit operating system can store 232 values, or approximately 4 GB of address space. The incorrect answers: A. 32 GB A 32-bit operating system does not contain 32 GB of memory addresses. B. 2 TB It's common to see 64-bit operating systems support terabytes of memory address space, but it's not available in a 32-bit operating system. C. 512 GB 32-bit operating systems support a maximum of 4 GB of memory. D. 128 GB 128 GB is well above the 32-bit address space of 4 GB. F. 16 GB 32-bit operating systems are limited to a maximum RAM of 4 GB. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.7 - Installing Applications https://professormesser.link/1102010701 Practice Exam C - Answers 369",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C74"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "A technician is troubleshooting a problem on a Linux server and needs to view the real-time CPU and memory utilization for each operating system process. Which of the following would provide this functionality?",
    "options": [
      "dig",
      "df",
      "cat",
      "top"
    ],
    "correct": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "top The linux top command is a common methods of viewing real-time information about CPU, RAM, and resource utilizations. This information is updated every second by default and can quickly identify highly utilized processes. The incorrect answers: A. dig The dig command is used to query DNS (Domain Name System) servers and view the configuration of the DNS database. B. df The df (Disk Free) command displays filesystem information and the free space available for each volume. C. cat The cat (Concatenate) command is used to combine files together on the screen or as part of a file. More information: 220-1102, Objective 1.11- Linux Commands https://professormesser.link/1102011101 380 Practice Exam C - Answers",
    "type": "single",
    "source_pdf": "comptia-220-1102-a-core-2-practice-exams-james-messer.pdf",
    "source_id": "C86"
  }
]